A Catalog of Instrumental Music Published Before ca. 1800 in the Alexander Mackay-Smith Collection of the University of Virginia
University of Virginia Library
- SIX SONATAS for two VIOLINS with a Thorough Bass for the HARPSICORD or VIOLONCELLO COMPOS'D BY Sigr. Gio. Batista St. Martini of Milan Opera Quinta. London. Printed for I. Walsh in Catharine Street in the Strand. Of whom may be had for two Violins and a Bass [list of works beginning with: "Twenty 
  Smith-Humphries, no. 1308.
  , December 2-4, 1756.
  - PRIMO
  - SECONDO
  - BASSO
- SIX SONATAS For two VIOLINS with a Thorough Bass for the Harpsicord or Violoncello Compos'd by Sigr. GIO. BATTISTA St. MARTINI of Milan SIGr. BRIOSCHI & other Masters. 3d. Set. London. Printed for I. Walsh in Catharine Street in the Strand., 1746; B/II, p. 364.; Three parts, folio, 231x173 (256x180): Violino Primo: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. Violino Secondo: Same as Violino Primo. Basso: Same as Violino Primo.
  Presto Assai C
  Menuetto Andante 3/4
  Largo e Piano C
  Andante Largo 12/8
  Trio sonatas. Selections; Bremner, Robert, d. 1789; Trio sonatas, 3rd set; Sammartini, Giovanni Battista, 1700 (ca.)-1775; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; London (England); Minuet; A; B♭; E♭; F; G; 12/8; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; 6/8; C; C|; Allegro; Andante; Andante largo; Largo; Largo e piano; Menuetto andante; Presto; Presto assai
  Smith-Humphries, no. 1313.
  , November 8, 1746.
  Sonatas 3, 4, and 5 are by Antonio Brioschi (Bathia Churgin, "Brioschi, Antonio," The New Grove, v. 3, p. 286).
  Nos. 1, 2, and 6 are spuriously attributed to Sammartini (Newell Jenkins and Bathia Churgin, "Sammartini, Giovanni Battista," The New Grove, v. 16, p. 456).
  "R.P." at beginning of Sonatas I and VI in Violino Primo; added in MS in Basso. The collection contains 2 more copies of this item. The third is without "R.P." in Violino Primo or Basso.
  - Violino Primo
  - Violino Secondo
  - Basso
- VI CONCERTI GROSSI con due Violini, Alto=Viola, e Violoncello obligati; e due Violini e Basso di Rinforzo: COMPOSTI da GIUSEPPE ST. MARTINI. Opra [backward "a"] II. Scolp: da B. Fortier. LONDRA MDCCXXXVIII., 1738; S698; Seven parts, quarto, 267x190 (278x196): Violino Primo di Concerto: Title, verso blank. Blank, [i]. Music, pp. 1-20. Unnumbered blanks between pp. 3 and 4, 6 and 7, 8 and 9. "Corno Primo" and "Corno Secondo", verso blank, bound in at end (see Notes, below). Violino Secondo di Concerto: Same as Violino Primo di Concertino, without extra part at end. Alto Viola: Title, verso blank. Blank, [i]. Music, pp. 1-16. Unnumbered blank between pp. 5 and 6. Basso di Concerto: Title, verso blank. Blank, [i]. Music, pp. 1-18. Unnumbered blank between pp. 8 and 9. Violino Primo di Rinforzo: Same as Alto Viola. Violino Secondo di Rinforzo: Same as Violino Primo di Rinforzo. Basso di Rinforzo: Title, verso blank. Blank, [i]. Music, pp. 1-15. Blank, [16]. Unnumbered blank between pp. 12 and 13.
  Allo. Assai 3/4
  CONCERTO II e
  Sostenuto C
  Minuet Affettuoso 3/4
  Allo. Assai 12/8
  CONCERTO V A
  Menuet Affetuoso 3/4
  Concerti grossi, op. 2; Sammartini, Giovanni Battista, 1700 (ca.)-1775; Fortier, B., fl. Ca. 1736-1740; London (England); Minuet; A; B♭; D; C; E; 12/8; 2/4; 3/4; C|; Adagio; Allegro; Allegretto; Allegretto assai; Andante; Andante spiritoso; Menuet affettuoso; Minuet; Minuet affettuoso; Sostenuto; Spiritoso
  Title-page.
  The leaf with parts for two horns, bound with the Violino Primo di Concerto, is marked "Marcia Allegro Sostenuto" and is an ad libitum part for a portion of the last movement of Concerto VI.
  - Violino Primo di Concerto
  - Violino Secondo di Concerto
  - Alto Viola
  - Basso di Concerto
  - Violino Primo di Rinforzo
  - Violino Secondo di Rinforzo
  - Basso di Rinforzo
- Six SOLOS For a GERMAN FLUTE VIOLIN or HAUTBOY with a Thorough Bass Composed by Sigr. Giuseppe St. Martini Op. XIII. LONDON Printed for John Johnson opposite Bow Church in Cheapside of whom may be had For the Violoncello. [list of works beginning with: "Cervetto's Solos Opera 3d" and ending with: "Nandot's Duets."], ca. 1760; S730; Score, folio, 263x182 (269x188): Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-24.
  Adagio C - Allegro assai 3/8
  SONATA [III] G
  Allegro moderto C
  Solos, flute, continuo, op. 13; Sammartini, Giovanni Battista, 1700 (ca.)-1775; Johnson, John, fl. 1754-1770; Johnson, John, fl. 1754-1770; London (England); Minuet; G; 12/8; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; C; Adagio; Allegro; Allegro assai; Allegro moderato; Andante; Grazioso; Minuet; Minuetto; Presto; [no indication]
- VI SONATE A TRE Due Flauti col Basso. DEDICATA al ALTEZZA REALE di FREDERICO Principe di Wallia Et Elettorale di Brunswik. da GIUSEPPE SAN MARTINI. MILANESE. OPERA PRIMA. Gravé par Labassée. Prix 6tt. A PARIS CHEZ Mr. Le Clerc le Cadet rue St. Honoré vis a vis l'Oratoire Chés le Bonnetier au Second. Le Sr. Le Clerc Marchand rue du Roule a la Croix d'Or. Madame Boivin Marchande rue St. Honoré a la Regle d'Or. Avec Privilege du Roy., 1743 or 1744; S717; Three parts, quarto, 250x179 (258x183): Flauto Traversiere Primo: Title, verso blank. Catalogue [see Notes, below], p. [1]. Music, pp. 2-15. Blank, [16]. Flauto Traversiere Secondo: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. Basso: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-14. Bound with nos. 25, 136, 190, 201, 202, and 235.
  Andante Stacato C
  Andante ed Amoroso 3/4
  Minuet Allegro 3/8
  Andante è Stacato 3/4
  Trio sonatas, op. 1; Sammartini, Giovanni Battista, 1700 (ca.)-1775; Le Clerc, Le Sr.; Le Clerc, le cadet; Le Clerc, Jean-Pantaléon, d. 1759; Le Clerc, Charles-Nicolas, 1697-1774; Croix d'Or; Règle d'Or; Boivin, Mme. (Elisabeth-Catherine Ballard), d. 1776; Labassée, Mme.; Paris (France); Minuet; C; D; G; B; 12/8; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; 6/8; C|; Adagio; Allegro; Allegro assai; Andante; Andante affettuoso; Andante stacato; Andante ed amoroso; Andante è staccato; Con spirito; Minuet allegro; Spiritoso
  Issued with catalogue of the same date (see Notes, below). Originally published in 1740, announced in Mercure de France, December, 1740 (Lesure/Catalogue, p. 562.); also appears in Le Clerc's catalogue of 1740 (Devriès, p. 250).
  - Flauto Traversiere Primo
  - Flauto Traversiere Secondo
  - Basso
- XII SONATE A due Violini, e Violoncello, e Cembalo, se piace, OPERA TERZA, Dedicata All' ALTEZZA REALE di Augusta Principessa di Vallia da Giuseppe San Martini Milanese MDCCXLIII LONDRA., 1743; S720; Three parts, quarto, 244x175 (262x188): Violino Primo: Title, verso blank. Letter of dedication, verso blank, pp. [i-ii]. Royal privilege, in letterpress, dated "the Tenth Day of June, 1736" and signed "HARRINGTON.", verso blank [leaf sewn in, possibly not part of the original publication], pp. [iii-iv]. Blank, [v]. Music, pp. 1-36. Blank, [37]. Violino Secondo: Title, verso blank. Blank, [i]. Music, pp. 1-36. Blank, [37]. Violoncello: Title, verso blank. Blank, [i]. Music, pp. 1-34. Blank, [35].
  Andte. Grazo. C
  Minuet spiritoso 3/8
  Andante Grazioso 12/8
  Andte. sostenuto 3/4
  Sarabanda Allo ma non tanto e Grazioso 3/4
  Allo. Sostenuto 3/4
  Spiritoso C - Allegro 6/8
  Minuet Grazioso 3/4
  Andante Allo. 2
  SONATA VIII D
  Allegro Comodo C
  SONATA IX a
  Andantino, e Cantabile 2/3
  Allegro Moderato 2
  Andante Sostenuto C
  Andante Grazzio 6/8
  Allo. Sostenuto C|
  SONATA XII g
  Spiritoso 6/8
  Rondò Allo. moderto. e Grazioso 3/8
  Pastorale Ande. sostenuto 12/8
  Trio sonatas, op. 3; Sammartini, Giovanni Battista, 1700 (ca.)-1775; London (England); Chaconne; Minuet; Rondo; Sarabande; A; B♭; D; E; G; C; 12/8; 2; 2/3; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; 6/8; C|; Allegro; Allegro comodo; Allegro moderato; Allegro sostenuto; Andante; Andante allegro; Andante amoroso; Andante grazioso; Andante sostenuto; Andantino; Andantino e cantabile; Ciaccona; Minuet grazioso; Minuet spiritoso; Pastorale andante sostenuto; Rondo allegro moderato e grazioso; Sarabanda allo ma non tanto e grazioso; Spiritoso; Tempo di minuet
  Announced in the
  , December 8, 1743, as "Printed for the Author, and sold by him ... and J. Walsh [etc.]" (Smith- Humphries no. 1328). Walsh later issued the work without date or dedication (Haas, item no. 570).
  - Violino Primo
  - Violino Secondo
  - Violoncello
- XII SONATE A due Violini, e Violoncello, e Cembalo, se piace, OPERA TERZA, Dedicata All' ALTEZZA REALE di Augusta Principessa di Vallia da Giuseppe San Martini London Printed for and Sold by I. Walsh Musick Printer & Instrument Maker to his Majesty in Catharine Street in the Strand., 1747; S722; Three parts, folio, 248x166 (263x185): Violino Primo: Title, verso blank. Letter of dedication as in no. 237, p. [i]. Music, pp. 1-36. Blank, [37]. Violino Secondo: Title. Music, pp. 1-36. Blank, [37]. Violoncello: Title. Music, pp. 1-34. Blank, [35].
  Trio sonatas, op. 3; Roberts, Henry, ca. 1710-ca. 1790; Sammartini, Giovanni Battista, 1700 (ca.)-1775; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; London (England); Chaconne; Minuet; Rondo; Sarabande; A; B♭; D; E; G; C; 12/8; 2; 2/3; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; 6/8; C|; Allegro; Allegro comodo; Allegro moderato; Allegro sostenuto; Andante; Andante allegro; Andante amoroso; Andante grazioso; Andante sostenuto; Andantino; Andantino e cantabile; Ciaccona; Minuet grazioso; Minuet spiritoso; Pastorale andante sostenuto; Rondo allegro moderato e grazioso; Sarabanda allo ma non tanto e grazioso; Spiritoso; Tempo di minuet
  Similar to Smith-Humphries, no. 1330, which was announced in
  , January 28, 1747.
  Another issue of no. 237 and an earlier state of Smith-Humphries no. 1330, in which pp. 4-5 of Violino Primo are re-engraved. At bottom of letter of dedication: "H Roberts sculp."
  - Violino Primo
  - Violino Secondo
  - Violoncello
- NOUVEAUX TRIOS, A DEUX FLUTES TRAVERSIERES, OU A DEUX VIOLONS, AVEC LA BASSE, CONTINUE. COMPOSÉS, et DEDIÉS, a son EXCELENCE MONSEIGNEUR CHARLES PAUL ERNEST, COMTE REGNANT de BENTHEIM, STEINFORD, TECKLENBOURG, et LIMBOURG, Seigneur de RHEDE, WEVELINGHOVE, HOYE, ALPE, et HELFFENSTEIN, Prevot Hereditaire de COLOGNE, Seigneur Hereditaire de BATENBOURG, et HAVICKERWEERD, GENERAL MAJOR de la CAVALLERIE au Service de sa MAJESTÉ BRITTANIQUE, Chevalier de l'Ordre de SAINT HUBERT. &c. &c. &c. Par le Sr: SANTO LAPIS, Maitre de Musique Italienne. a AMSTERDAM. 1756 Pieter Mol, Sculp:, L661; Three parts, quarto, 246x209 (258x220)
  - Primo Flauto, o Violino
  - Secondo Flauto, o Violino
  - Basso
- Six SONATAS for one FLUTE & two HOBOYS or two VIOLINS with a VIOL BASS and a THOROUGH BASS for the HARPSICORD & ARCHLUTE Compos'd by Mr. Christian Schickhard London Printed for I. Walsh Servant in Ordinary to his Majesty at ye Harp & Hoboy in Catherine Street in ye Strand. and I. Hare at ye Viol and Flute in Cornhill near the Royall Exchange., 1715; S1571; Five parts, folio, 269x169 (272x175): FLAUTO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-12. Blank, [13]. Unnumbered blank between pp. 9 and 10. HAUTBOIS PRIMO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-11. Blank, [12]. HAUTBOIS SECONDO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-9. Blank, [10]. VIOLA DI GAMBA: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. ORGANO: Same as VIOLA DI GAMBA. FLAUTO has in MS in lower right corner of title-page: "s6-0".
  Piu Vivace 3/4
  Sonatas, recorder, oboes (2), continuo, op. 5; Schickhard, Johann Christian, ca. 1680-1762; Hare, John, d. 1725; Harp and Hoboy; Viol and Flute; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; London (England); Minuet; C; D; F; G; 3/2; 3/4; 6/8; Adagio; Allegro; Cantabile; Minuet; Piu vivace; Un poco vivace; Vivace
  Smith no. 467.
  , August 4-5, 1715.
  - FLAUTO
  - HAUTBOIS PRIMO
  - HAUTBOIS SECONDO
  - VIOLA DI GAMBA
  - ORGANO
- SEI DUETTI PER VIOLINO E VIOLONCELLO Composti da F SCHWINDL OPERA VI. À LA HAYE Chez B. HUMMEL À LONDRE Chez MR R: BREMNER, 1770; S2594; Three parts, quarto, 219x141 (275x213): VIOLINO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. VIOLONCELLO: Same as VIOLINO. Unfigured.
  Allegro con Brio C
  Menutto grazioso 3/4
  Allegro con Brio 2/4
  Menuetto Gratioso 3/4
  Arioso 2/4
  Allegro Molto C|
  Andantino Espressivo 2/4
  Adagio 3/8 - Presto 2/4
  Duets, violin, violoncello, op. 6; Schwindl, Friedrich, 1737-1786; Bremner, Robert, d. 1789; Hummel, Burchard, 1731-1797; London (England); Hague (Netherlands); Arioso; Minuet; A; B♭; C; D; F; G; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; C|; Adagio; Allegro moderato; Allegro molto; Allegro con brio; Andantino espressivo; Arioso; Larghetto; Largo; Menuetto grazioso; Presto; Tempo di menuetto
  Gravenhaegse courant
  , January 31, 1770 (Johansson/Hummel, v. 1, p. 28).
  - VIOLINO
  - VIOLONCELLO
- Six SONATAS FOR TWO GERMAN FLUTES with a Thorough Bass for the HARPSICHORD Composed by F: Schwindl OPERA III LONDON Printed by WELCKER in Gerrard Street St. Ann's Soho Where may be had for two German Flutes and a Bass [list of works beginning with: "Six Trios by Barthelemon" and ending with: "With the greatest Variety of New Musick by the most Admir'd Authors."], ca. 1770; S2572; Three parts, quarto, 258x184 (267x193): PRIMO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. SECONDO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-10. BASSO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-9. Blank, [10].
  Vivace Tempo di Menuetto 3/4
  Allegro Vivace C
  Fuga 3/8
  Vivace Tempo di menuetto 3/4
  Arioso con Variatione 2/4
  Trio sonatas, op. 3; Schwindl, Friedrich, 1737-1786; Welcker, Peter, d. 1775; Welcker, Peter, d. 1775; Welcker, Peter, d. 1775; London (England); Arioso; Fugue; Minuet; Variations; A; C; D; G; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; C|; Allegro; Allegro vivace; Andante; Arioso con variazione; Fuga; Largo; Vivace; Vivace tempo di menuetto
  - PRIMO
  - SECONDO
  - BASSO
- Six SONATAS FOR TWO VIOLINS and BASS. Dedicated to Monsr. Le COMTE de HEIDEN de REINESTEIN Gentilhomme de la Chambre de S.A.S. Monseigr. Le Prince d'Orange & Nassau &c. BY F: Schwindl Opa. 5th. pr. 5s/ LONDON Printed & Sold by J: LONGMAN & Co. No. 26, Cheapside, where may be had lately Publish'd, for Violins [list of works beginning with: "Richter's Quartetts" and ending with: "Miller's Solo's & double Tonguing"], 1769; S2575; Three parts, quarto, 268x193 (280x202): VIOLINO PRIMO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. VIOLINO SECONDO: Same as VIOLINO PRIMO. BASSO: Same as VIOLINO PRIMO.
  Rondeaux Andantino 2/4
  Largetto 3/4
  Allegro ma non tanto 2/4
  Trio sonatas, op. 5; Schwindl, Friedrich, 1737-1786; J. Longman & Co. [London, England]; J. Longman & Co. [London, England]; London (England); Minuet; Rondo; A; B♭; C; D; E; F; 2/4; 3/4; 6/8; C|; Allegro; Allegro moderato; Allegro ma non tanto; Andante; Andantino; Grazioso; Larghetto; Largo; Minuetto; Presto; Rondeaux andantino
  Hummel was the first to publish these works, in 1769 (Johansson/Hummel, v. 1, p. 76). Longman & Co. became Longman, Lukey and Co. that same year, making it possible to date this publication with some certainty to that year.
  - VIOLINO PRIMO
  - VIOLINO SECONDO
  - BASSO
- Six DIVERTIMENTOS for two VIOLINS and a BASS Composed in an easy and familiar Style by Pugnani, Vachon, Borghi, & Aprile. Pr. 5s. LONDON. Printed for Wm. Napier corner of Lancaster Court, STRAND., 1772; B/II, p. 154. P5608; Three parts, quarto, 243x193 (275x200): VIOLINO PRIMO: Title, [1]. Music, pp. 2-7. Blank, [8]. VIOLINO SECONDO: Same as VIOLINO PRIMO. BASSO: Same as VIOLINO PRIMO.
  DIVERTIMENTO I [by Gaetano Pugnani:Zschinsky no. 80a] E♭
  DIVERTIMENTO II F
  DIVERTIMENTO III G
  DIVERTIMENTO IV [by Gaetano Pugnani: Zschinsky no. 80d] E
  Allegretto Espressivo C
  DIVERTIMENTO V F
  DIVERTIMENTO VI E♭
  Divertimenti, violins (2), continuo; Aprile, Giuseppe, 1732-1813; Divertimenti; Borghi, Luigi, b. ca. 1745; Trio sonatas, Z. 80a and 80d; Pugnani, Gaetano, 1731-1798; Trio sonatas. Selections; Vachon, Pierre, 1731-1803; Napier, William, 1740?-1812; London (England); Minuet; E; E♭; F; G; 2/4; 3/4; C; C|; Allegretto; Allegretto espressivo; Andante; Andantino; Larghetto; Minuetto; Tempo di minuetto
  Boris Schwarz ("Pugnani, Gaetano," The New Grove, v. 15, p. 447) has tentatively attributed nos. 1 and 4 to Pugnani.
  - VIOLINO PRIMO
  - VIOLINO SECONDO
  - BASSO
- Six Sonatas for two Violins & a Bass COMPOSED BY Theodor Smith. London Printed by WELCKER in Gerrard Street St. Ann's Soho Where may be had by the same Author [list of works beginning with: "Six Quartets for two Violins or one Violin, a German Flute, Tenor, and Bass." and ending with: "eight Lessons by Gladwin. with the greatest Variety of New Musick by the most Eminent Masters."], ca. 1770; S3753; Three parts, folio, 260x185 (266x188): VIOLINO PRIMO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. VIOLINO SECONDO: Same as VIOLINO PRIMO. BASSO: Same as VIOLINO PRIMO.
  Allegretto Cantabile C
  Rondo Vivace un Poco 2/4
  Trio sonatas; Smith, Theodore, ca. 1740-ca. 1810; Welcker, Peter, d. 1775; Welcker, Peter, d. 1775; Welcker, Peter, d. 1775; London (England); Minuet; Rondo; A; B♭; C; D; G; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; C|; Adagio; Allegretto; Allegretto cantabile; Allegro; Allegro maestoso; Allegro moderato; Andante grazioso; Larghetto; Minuetto; Rondo vivace un poco; Tempo di minuetto
  - VIOLINO PRIMO
  - VIOLINO SECONDO
  - BASSO
- Six SONATAS for two GERMAN FLUTES or VIOLINS with a Bass for the Violoncello or Harpsicord. Compos'd by Sigr. ANTONIO GUGLIELMO SOLNIZ. Opera Seconda. Just Publish'd, Six Sonatas for 2 Violins & a Bass by ye same Author, Op: 1ma. London. Printed for I. Walsh, in Catharine Street, in the Strand. Of whom may be had, Just Publish'd, For 2 German Flutes and a Bass. [list of works beginning with: "Chinzer's Sonatas" and ending with: "Hasse's Solos"], 1751; S3937 ("Base"); Three parts, folio, 248x179 (254x184): PRIMO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-12. SECONDO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-9. Blank, [10]. BASSO: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-11. Blank, [12].
  Trio sonatas, op. 2; Solnitz, Anton Wilhelm, ca. 1708-1752 or 3; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; London (England); Minuet; A; C; D; G; E; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; 6/8; Adagio; Allegro; Andante; Cantabile; Largo; Menuet andante; Presto; Vivace
  Smith-Humphries, no. 1390.
  , March 29, 1751.
  - PRIMO
  - SECONDO
  - BASSO
- SIX SONATAS for a German Flute a Violin and a Thorough Bass for the Harpsichord or Violoncello Compos'd in a familiar Stile by Mr. Spourni LONDON Printed for and sold by John SImpson at the Bass Viol and Flute in Sweeting's Alley opposite the East Door of the Royal Exchange. Where may be had just publishd, [list of works beginning with: "Six SONATAS for two German Flutes, compos'd on purpose for the Improvement of the Hand in a Taste natural to the Instrument, by Sigr. Groneman." and ending with: "Six SONATAS for two Violins and a Bass, compos'd by Sigr. Gio. Battista St. Martini."], 1744; S4187; Three parts, folio, 276x193 (287x198): Traversa: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. Violino: Same as Traversa. Basso: Title, verso blank. Blank, [1]. Music, pp. 2-7. Blank, [8].
  Allo. ma non Presto 2/4
  Allegrezza 3/8
  Allego 3/4
  Aria Cantabile 3/4
  Arioso Andante 3/4
  Allegretto Tempo di Menuetto 3/4
  Andante 3/4 - Allo. 3/4
  Andante Tempo di Pastorale 6/8
  Allegretto Presto C
  Trio sonatas; Spourni, Wenceslaus Joseph; Bass Viol & Flute; Simpson, John, fl. 1734-1749; Simpson, John, fl. 1734-1749; London (England); Aria; Arioso; Minuet; A; D; G; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; 6/8; C; Adagio; Allegro; Allegretto presto; Allegretto tempo di menuetto; Allegrezza; Allegro ma non presto; Andante; Andante tempo di pastorale; Andantino; Aria cantabile; Arioso andante; Menuetto; Tempo di menuetto
  - Traversa
  - Violino
  - Basso
- SIX TRIO DONT TROIS CONCERTANS ET TROIS A GRAND ORCHÊSTRE Pour deux Violons et Basse DEDIÉS A Monsieur RANDON DE LA TOUR Trésorier Général des Maisons de leurs Majestés PAR A. STAMITZ Musicien Ordinaire du Roy. 3e. Livre de Trio de Violon. Prix 9tt. A PARIS Chez M. BOYER, Rue de Richelieu, à la Clef d'Or, Passage du Caffé de Foy. Chez Made. Le Menu, Rue du Roulle, à la Clef d'Or Ecrit par Ribiere, 1786; S4388; Three parts, folio, 258x193 (264x194): Violino Primo: Title, verso catalogue [Johansson/French facs. 95]. Catalogue [Johansson/French facs. 96], [1]. Music, pp. 2-[13]. Blank, [14]. Pages [12] and [13] incorrectly numbered as 21 and 31. Violino Secondo: Title, [1]. Music, pp. 2-13. Blank, [14]. Basso: Same as Violino Secondo. Title-page of Violino Primo signed in lower right: "Boyer".
  TRIO I Concertant D
  TRIO II à Grand Orchestre C
  Allegro Gratioso 2/4
  TRIO III Concertant B♭
  TRIO IV à Grand Orchêstre E♭
  Allo. assai 6/8
  Andante Gratioso 2/4
  TRIO V Concertant C
  TRIO VI à Grand Orchêstre F
  Trios. Selections; Stamitz, Anton, b. 1750; Boyer, Charles-Georges; Le Menu, Made.; Ribiere; Paris (France); Minuet; Rondo; B♭; C; D; E♭; F; 2; 2/4; 3/4; 6/8; C|; Allegro; Allegro grazioso; Allegro assai; Andante grazioso; Minuet; Minuetto; Rondo allegretto
  Issued with catalogues of the same date. Appears in Boyer's catalogue of 1787 (Johansson/French, facs. 97) but not in another catalogue of 1786 (facs. 95).
  - Violino Primo
  - Violino Secondo
  - Basso
- SIX CONCERTOS IN SEVEN PARTS FOR FOUR VIOLINS, a TENOR VIOLIN, a VIOLONCELLO, with a THOROUGH BASS for the HARPSICORD. COMPOS'D BY John Stanley Batchelor of Musick, Organist of St. Andrews, and the Temple. London. Printed for I. Walsh, in Catharine Street, in the Strand., 1745; S4673; Seven parts, folio, 228x176 (257x185): Violino Primo del Concertino: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-19. Unnumbered blank between pp. 10 and 11. Violino Secondo del Concertino: Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-13. Blank, [14]. Violoncello: Same as Violino Secondo del Concertino. Violino Primo Ripieno: Title, verso blank. Blank, [i]. Music, pp. 1-12. Blank, [13]. Violino Secondo Ripieno: Same as Violino Primo Ripieno. Alto Viola: Same as Violino Primo Ripieno. Basso Ripieno: Same as Violino Primo Ripieno. At end of Violino Primo de Concertino, Violino Secondo del Concertino, Violoncello, and Basso Ripieno: "Phillips Sculpt."
  CONCERTO II b
  Adagio 3/2 - Allo. Moderato C|
  CONCERTO III G
  CONCERTO V a
  Largo 3/4 - Allegro C|
  Allo. Moderato 3/4
  Concerti grossi, op. 2; Stanley, John, 1712-1786; Phillips, John; Phillips, Sarah; Walsh, John, 1665 or 6-1736; London (England); B♭; D; G; A; B; 3/2; 3/4; 3/8; C; C|; Adagio; Allegro; Allegro moderato; Andante; Largo
  Smith-Humphries, no. 1412.
  , January 14, 1745.
  - Violino Primo del Concertino
  - Violino Secondo del Concertino
  - Violoncello
  - Violino Primo Ripieno
  - Violino Secondo Ripieno
  - Alto Viola
  - Basso Ripieno
- Eight Solo's for a German Flute, Violin or Harpsicord COMPOS'D By John Stanley M.B. Organist of the Temple and St. Andrew's. Opera Prima LONDON Printed for & sold by J. Johnson Musick Seller in Cheapside & at all the Musick Shops Where may be had lately publish'd Six SOLOS or Lessons for the Harpsicord by Mr. Stanley Opera Quarta Price.....01.5s.0d Twelve CONCERTO'S for the Harpsicord or Organ by Mr. Felton, in two Books, Price of each, ..0.5.0, 1740; S4671; Score, quarto, 183x273 (196x279): Title, verso blank. Music, pp. (1)-(33). Blank, [34].
  SOLO I d
  SOLO II g
  Ada: Staco. 3/4
  SOLO III G
  SOLO IV D
  SOLO V C
  SOLO VI D
  Allegro Andante C|
  SOLO VII d
  Gavot Allegro C
  SOLO VIII e
  Solos, flute, continuo, op. 1; Stanley, John, 1712-1786; Johnson, John, fl. 1754-1770; Johnson, John, fl. 1754-1770; London (England); Gavotte; Minuet; Siciliana; C; D; G; E; 12/8; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; 6/8; C|; Adagio staccato; Adagio; Allegro; Allegro andante; Gavot allegro; Largo; Minuet allegro; Minuet andante; Siciliana
  Includes figured bass.